Often in coding you will need your code to
コーディングにおいては、条件にもとづいて
make a decision based on a condition.
判定をする必要性がしばしば出てきます。
Think of having a cup of coffee.
たとえばコーヒー カップがあったとします。
When it's first made the water is boiling.
最初に出来あがったばかりは、沸騰しています。
You might want to check if it's ready to drink.
そこで飲んでも問題ないか確認したいとしましょう。
If the coffee's temperature is greater the
もしコーヒーの水温が
hottest temperature you're willing to
飲んでも良いと考える温度よりも高い場合は
drink it at then you won't drink it.
当然に飲まないでしょう。
An extension of the if statement is
if 文を拡張したものが
the if-else statement.
if-else 文です。
In our coffee example the else statement
コーヒーの例でいうと、 else 文は
might be that you drink the coffee.
コーヒーを飲んでも問題ないと判断することかもしれません。
This action will not be executed when the
このアクションというのは、
first condition is not satisfied.
最初の条件が満たされない場合に実行されるものです。
So if the coffee is not too hot to drink
このため、コーヒーが飲むにあたって温度が十分低ければ
then we drink it.
コーヒーを飲むことになります。
This can be further extended by making
さらにこの if 文を拡張するには
the else statement a conditional
else 文の中で
by using another 'if'.
もう一つの if 文を使用します。
With our coffee example, if the coffee
コーヒーの例でいえば、もしコーヒーが
was too hot we wouldn't drink it,
熱すぎる場合は、飲みませんでした。
but if we'd left it too long, and if
さらに考えてみると、コーヒーを
it had gotten cold then we might not
放置した場合も冷めてしまって、
drink it either.
やっぱり飲まないことになります。
However if neither of these conditions
しかし、これらの条件が両方とも満たされなければ、
are satisfied, that is, that the
言いかえると、
coffee is neither too hot nor too cold
コーヒーが熱くもなく冷めてもいなければ
then the coffee is at an appropriate
コーヒーは飲むにあたって
drinking temperature. Let's take a look
適温だといえます。それでは
at this in action.
このスクリプトを実際に動かしてみましょう。
Now that it's dropped below my hot limit
この時点で飲んでも良い温度まで下がっているので
the coffee is just right.
コーヒーは適温です。
But if I wait until it's below the cold limit
しかし、冷めすぎた温度まで下がると
the coffee's too cold.
コーヒーは冷めて飲めないことになります。
So you can use 'if' statements in this way to make
まとめると、 if 文をこのように使用すれば
decisions within your code as to
コードの中でどうするか
what it should do.
判断させることが出来ます。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)